# Bayazid Alam Siddiqui

Sales & Distribution Professional



Address 41, North Goran. Dhaka, 13, 1219

Phone 8801790243103

E-mail bayazid.alam16@gmail.com

Experienced Distribution Sales Management professional with a demonstrated history of working in the consumer goods industry for 6+ years. Skilled in distribution management, sales operation, trade marketing, RTM with a BBA degree focused in Marketing.

## **Work History**

## 2021-08 – Area Sales Manager

#### Current MGH Group(Proctor & Gamble Business Unit), Rajshahi

- Plan, Implement and Expansion coverage strategies through distributor, alternative route to market and new channels.
- Managing distributor with proper investment, stock, infrastructure and ROI management.
- Plan and achieve both secondary and Primary sales target by following up category, brand and channel wise growth performance.
- Ensuring product quality & customer service by reducing section drop, market return and product expiry.
- Winning with team by performance and on the job training culture within team also increasing team's productivity by engagement activities.

## 2018-03 - Senior Territory Manager 2021-07 Marico Bangladesh Limited, Pabna, Rajshahi

- Driving both primary &secondary along with company's growth vision.
- Ensuring profitability of business partner alongside ensuring company's business.
- Adherence to RTM and alternative RTM model of the business.
- Successful & proper execution and implementation of Trade activities.
- Channel growth for priority categories and in priority channels.
- DFF's capability development through on the job training and training programs.
- Successfully executed Marico Priority Store with above 95% successful outlet.
- Completed total 15 NPLP's in total tenure of 3.6 years.
- Initiated a trade-marketing program of Non Hair Oil segment in Bogra Outer HQ.

- Successfully launched SnD plan in MBL Pabna which consists 13% incremental Outlet over current base for major growth driver in FY 2021-2022.
- Launched Split Calling in Ullahpara and Shirajganj town along with other RTM Implementation.
- Regionally 2nd Highest 16.56% YTD growth achiever in MBL from Bogra Outer in West Region in 2018-2019

## 2017-07 - **Territory Sales Officer**

#### 2018-02 Reckitt Benckiser Bangladesh Limited, CoxsBazar, Chittagong

- Nationally H-2 champion in 2017 with nationally ever-highest 31% YTD growth for Reckitt Benckiser Bangladesh Limited.
- Nationally top performer for consecutive 5 month in 2017-2018 for Reckitt Benckiser Bangladesh Limited.
- Successful changeover of DB in 1 town and bring back to growth journey by 1 month.
- Implementation and proper utilization of alterative channel NGO & International Organizations in Coxbazar Territory.

## 2015-10 - **Territory Officer**

#### 2016-08 Dhaka Tobacco Industries, Norsinghdi, Dhaka

- Working as a Territory Officer at Dhaka Tobacco Industries under Akij Corporation Limited.
- Responsible for sales, distribution and trade marketing activities of assigned Territory.
- Looked after total of 83 DFF's.
- Awarded by Japan Tobacco International for Nationally highest achievement in April 2016.

#### 2014-05 - **Intern**

2014-08 Grameenphone Limited, Dhaka, Dhaka

#### Education

2009-05 -

2015-04	East West University – Dhaka
2006-09 - 2008-09	<b>HSC: Business Studies</b> Rifles Public School & Collage - Dhaka
2000-01 -	SSC: Business Studies
2006-09	Ideal School & Collage – Dhaka

**BBA: Marketing** 

#### **Personal Information**

Father: Badrul Alam SiddiquiMother: Rawshan Ara Begum

• Date of Birth: 16th, December 1991.

Marital Status: Married Nationality: Bangladeshi

## Skills

Analytical problem solver	Excellent
Business development and planning	Excellent
Efficient New product Development Process	Excellent
Self Motivated	Excellent
Flexibility according to situation	Excellent
Quality to lead and foresee	Excellent
Proficient in MS Office	
Bengali	Excellent
English	Excellent

## **Certifications**

Languages

2018-11 TDOM Training-Marico Bangladesh Limited

2019-11 Analytical Based Decision Making-EnParadigm

## Reference

#### Muhammad Mustafizur Rahman

National Sales Manager

Reckitt Benckiser Bangladesh Limited

Gulshan-1, Dhaka. Phone: 01777759002

S.M. Reza E Rabby

Senior Manager,RTM

JTI,Bangladesh.

Phone: 01755543959